JOSIAH BROWN

josiah.webdev@gmail.com | 682-239-6862 | Fort Worth, TX 76707

Portfolio Website

josiahbrown.com

Summary

Motivated Web Developer with in-depth knowledge of JavaScript, ReactJS, REST API's, HTML, and CSS. Experience writing code in multiple languages and building custom React web apps for clients. Known for always learning something new, completing projects with excellence, and possessing a strong work ethic.

Programming Languages/Frameworks

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- Python
- Bash Scripting
- C++
- Java
- Swift
- Verilog
- Linux Command Line

- React.js
- Node.js
- Git
- Tailwind
- Jest, React Testing Library
- MongoDB
- Express.js
- p5.js
- Microsoft Office
- WordPress

Experience

9 06/2022 - 08/2022

Panther City Leather Fort Worth, TX

Full Stack Developer

- Developed both back-end and front-end of panthercityleather.com.
- Completed code debugging and implemented fixes to resolve problems based on priority system.
- Began SEO optimization for client using Google Search Console.
- View the completed site on panthercityleather.com

06/2021 - 05/2022

Volunteer

Free Burma Rangers Chiang Mai, Thailand

- Built and installed off-grid solar power systems.
- Developed custom software solutions to assist in trainings and office efficiency.
- Created and edited videos describing human rights violations occurring in Myanmar.
- Piloted a drone on the front lines of a war zone to obtain information regarding enemy position.
- Passed 2 intense fitness tests required by the organization to be included on a mission.
- Studied Thai and obtained an "Advanced Thai Language" certificate from Manna Thai Language School in less than 8 months.

05/2020 - 08/2020

Qorvo

Richardson, TX

Product Quality Engineering Intern

- Organized, archived, and created file management system for computer chips that had been previously tested by the product quality team.
- Analyzed data and technical documents to compose a list of parts to be converted to new epoxy

- Created and managed a database used by the PQE team to keep track of all tested products.
- Created a summarizing document and presented to the PQE team on the PQE standard stress tests.

Brown Woodworking
Fort Worth, TX

Business Owner

- Designed, produced, and sold original woodworking projects (fountain pens, segmented vases, rocking chairs, dining tables, shutters, and 14' bookcases).
- Built projects observing ergonomics, end-user functionality, and long product life.
- Developed all marketing and sales functions: kept track of all costs, set prices, photographed items, wrote product descriptions, managed packaging & shipping, and created a shop on Etsy.
- Interacted with customers frequently and developed a very high customer satisfaction rating. I never received less than a 5-star review.

Education and Training

05/2021

Bachelor of Science in Electrical And Computer Engineering

Waco, TX

Baylor University

- 3.95 GPA
- Summa Cum Laude
- Minor in Mathematics
- Additional Coursework in Computer Science, Digital Logic Design, Electronic Design, Signals and Systems

Languages

Thai:

Limited

Certifications

- Certificate of Completion (2022): The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp
- Certificate of Completion (2021): Linux Command Line Mastery
- Certificate of Completion (2021): Shell Scripting
- Advanced Thai Language Certification for Foreigner (2022)